# Brier S. Gallihugh, M.S.

989-423-6118 | Email: gallihughou@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio | Lancaster, OH 43130

#### **SUMMARY**

Lam an avnerianced social psychology researcher and dectoral condidate specializing in work recording prainting and

I am an experienced social psychology researcher and doctoral candidate specializing in work regarding prejudice and discrimination. I bring +7 years of experience in data science (including experimental design) and +2 years of psychometric experience resulting in +15 studies, 8 presentations across national and regional conferences, and 2 manuscripts. I am seeking to use my data science expertise to provide data driven insights and help advance organizational goals and objectives.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Language Skills: R | SPSS | SQL | Python | Git
   R Libraries: Tidyverse (e.g., dplyr and ggplot2)
- **Technical Writing:** Rmarkdown | Quarto
- **Software**: GitHub
- Statistical Modeling: SEM | Meta Analysis | Regression | Correlation | T-Test | ANOVA | Mediation & Moderation
- Psychometrics: Scale Construction | Scale Development | Scale Validation | EFA | CFA
- Other: Dynamic Computational Modeling | Data Cleaning | Research Design | Data Analysis | Experimental Design

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Quantitative Researcher, Ohio University | Athens, OH

August 2020 - Present

- Designed, cleaned, analyzed, and created visualizations for +10 research studies using R to gain insight into human behavior and attitudes as a doctoral level student.
- Applied regression analyses, ANOVA and moderation analyses to investigate human behavior and intervention effectiveness.
- Disseminated analytical insights at regional and national science conferences in the form of 3 presentations and 3 talks at departmental colloquiums and regional psychological science conferences in addition to one registered report.
- Designed and taught a hybrid modality R training workshop consisting of 10 modules across 2 days to +15 graduate students.

# Quantitative Researcher, Eastern Michigan University | Ypsilanti, MI

**August 2017 – August 2021** 

- Designed, cleaned, analyzed, and created visualizations for 5 research studies using R to gain insight into human behavior and attitudes as a masters level student.
- Applied regression analyses, ANOVA and psychometrics to investigate human behavior, evaluate intervention effectiveness and construct and investigate the validity and reliability of a new psychological measure.
- Disseminated analytical insights at regional and national science conferences in the form of 2 presentations.

#### SELECTED PROJECTS

# Black Lives Matter Support (BLM)

**August 2020 - Present** 

Designed, implemented and analyzed behavioral data across 5 studies investigating predictors of support for the BLM movement. Regression analysis suggested high multiculturalism and low assimilation beliefs positively predict support. A link to the source code repository can be found <u>HERE</u>

# R Workshop Website

May 2023 – July 2023

• Designed and launched a R workshop companion site using Quarto and GitHub to provide reference materials (and video recordings) for how to run inferential statistics with R. The companion website can be found HERE

# Christian Privilege Scale

August 2018 - August 2021

Designed, implemented and analyzed a scale development project to create a valid measure of Christian privilege awareness
among Christian samples. Initial factor analysis and correlation analysis suggest the scale captures the intended privilege
metric. A link to the source code repository can be found HERE

#### PUBLICATIONS AND OTHER MEDIA

Gallihugh, B. & Rios, K. (2023). Inter-ethnic ideologies as predictors of black lives and all lives matter. In Preparation

Mackey, C. D., Gallihugh, B., Rios, K., & Gervais, W. M. (2023). Faithless found: Replication and extension of Gervais (2011). The International Journal for the Psychology of Religion. Accepted In Principle (as a registered report)

Gallihugh, B. (2023). Statistical Analyses in R: A Two Day Crash Course. Hybrid Workshop at Ohio University. Materials can be found **HERE** 

# **EDUCATION**

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) in Experimental Psychology

Ohio University (Athens, OH) Expected: December 2024

Master of Science (M.S.) in General Experimental Psychology

Eastern Michigan University (Ypsilanti, MI)

Saginaw Valley State University (Saginaw, MI)

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Psychology

August 2020 - Present

August 2017 - August 2021

August 2012 - May 2017